# **Gregory Pratt**

10 QUEENS COURT, GREAT PRESTON, LEEDS. WEST YORKSHIRE, **LS26 8DD** 

gregory.pratt@me.com

**TELEPHONE** (0113) 2873225 **MOBILE** 07543 654 323

### Profile & Background

After completing my Masters at Leeds University, I started working for Pace Microtechnology as a developer. After 2 successful years at Pace, I moved to HBOS plc as a Web Developer. In the 4 years I was at HBOS, in an environment that is both competitive and highly professional, I proved myself to be a determined, motivated individual, who relishes a challenge and is proud of the quality work I produce. I am currently working for StepChange; a charity helping people with problem debt as a Technical Champion.

#### Education

Information Systems MSc Masters Degree - Leeds University, 2003 - 2004

Software Engineering BSc Degree - Hull University, 2000 - 2003

### Skills

Client side	Server Side
• HTML5	• C# / VB.NET and ASP.NET MVC Web API
JavaScript (inc. AngularJS and jQuery)	• REST API (inc. Hypermedia)
CSS3 (inc. LESS and SASS)	NoSQL (Firebase/Mongo)
Protractor (Testing Framework)	• SQL Server
Consumption of HAL based REST APIs	NHibernate
	• NServiceBus
Misc	

- Github
- Grunt
- BDD (Gherkin syntax)
- Web Storm
- Visual Studio
- TFS

### **Professional Experience**

#### WEB DEVELOPER, SYSTEMS DEVELOPMENT

#### STEPCHANGE DEBT CHARITY, LEEDS, MARCH 2011 - PRESENT

Working as a web developer at StepChange, I have been instrumental in a series of projects, both internal and external facing, providing technical expertise and producing quality pieces of work. I have been recognised as one of the strongest technically capable members of the team and as such currently fulfil the role of "Technical Champion".

In my role as Technical Champion - which I gained in recognition of my talent - I have had the responsibility of producing and presenting the department's Mobile Strategy and the charity's new Front End Development Approach.

The Mobile Strategy covered a range of topics from systems analysis, responsive user interface design, analysis of web traffic, mobile first development techniques, implications to system testing and training opportunities. I presented 3 high-level approaches with equally balanced supporting information to Senior Management.

The new Front End Development Approach involved a rather large shift in not only technologies but techniques also. With development within the charity being primarily .NET based my proposal to remove .NET from all green field consuming applications and replace it with a back to basics HTML, CSS and JavaScript stack was viewed as rather radical. The proposal involved utilising AngularJS to perform the heavy lifting that .NET would usually provide. It also included a new testing approach, training journey for mobile first and AngularJS and the development of a front end library of AngularJS directives.

My secondary responsibilities currently include mentoring fellow developers, acting as a sounding board for Senior Management and conducting recruitment interviews.

# ECOMMERCE TECHNICAL LEAD, MAJOR PROJECTS TEAM, ADM INSURANCE LLOYDS BANKING GROUP, HALIFAX, SEPTEMBER 2009 - MARCH 2011

In recognition of previously successful projects, experience and personal performance, I was assigned as the ECommerce Technical Lead to the Lloyds / HBOS Integration project. The project goal was to provide a fully configurable white-labelled web platform that all brands under the new Lloyds Banking Group could utilise to sell Home Insurance online.

I had a variety of responsibilities such as producing accurate project estimates, mentoring junior members of the team, guiding senior members of the team technically, producing technical low level designs, estimating, prioritising and creating solutions to change requests, in addition to writing quality production strength code.

As a Technical Lead, good relationships need to exist between the Project Leader, Business Analysts, System Analysts, other Technical Leads, Team Managers, members of the Business Team and most importantly the developers who I was responsible for. Each relationship requires a different type of interaction and diplomacy.

# SENIOR DEVELOPER, ECOMMERCE DEVELOPMENT TEAM, INSURANCE & INVESTMENT HALIFAX BANK OF SCOTLAND, HALIFAX, SEPTEMBER 2008 - SEPTEMBER 2009

I was promoted to a Senior Developer after a successful project as a Lead Developer.

I mentored new developers whilst being involved in multiple quick to production projects designed to facilitate business promotions, service protection and live maintenance. Live maintenance in particular requires good and broad understanding of the systems to provide accurate diagnosis and estimates of the work required to fix the problems.

# DEVELOPER, ECOMMERCE DEVELOPMENT TEAM, INSURANCE & INVESTMENT HALIFAX BANK OF SCOTLAND, COPLEY, HALIFAX, NOVEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2008

I joined HBOS as a developer. My first task was to introduce a new web application written in C# and ASP.NET v2. Against very tight deadlines and technical challenges we were able to produce a quality application on time and in budget.

My first project as a Lead Developer was to take ownership of new web applications for Halifax Home, Bank of Scotland Home and Halifax Landlord Insurance products. As a Lead Developer I was expected to provide guidance to other developers who were new to .NET. This was a stretch activity for me at the time as I had only recently expanded my own skill set in my transition from Java to .NET.

JUNIOR DEVELOPER, IT DEPARTMENT PACE MICROTECHNOLOGY, SALTAIRE, BRADFORD, NOVEMBER 2004 - NOVEMBER 2006

## **Hobbies & Interests**

Family days out, playing football each week, films, go-karting and personal projects such as:

Stack Overflow profile: http://stackoverflow.com/users/1130266/greg

Online CV: <a href="http://careers.stackoverflow.com/gregorypratt">http://careers.stackoverflow.com/gregorypratt</a>

GitHub profile: <a href="https://github.com/GrumpyWizards">https://github.com/GrumpyWizards</a>

### Referrals

Available on request.